

## Varvara Lazarenko

**Address** Nijmegen, The Netherlands

**Telephone** +31 6 2662 9839 **E-mail** varlazoa@gmail.com

**Date of birth** 29.12.1998 (26 years) **LinkedIn** www.linkedin.com/in/varvara-lazo

#### **PERSONAL STATEMENT**

I am a curious and dedicated graduate with a Master's degree in Medical Biology, driven by a passion for advancing healthcare through science. My experience spans both fundamental research and clinical trial development. With a solid biomedical background and a keen interest in sharing knowledge, I am motivated to learn new research methods and to grow within the clinical, pharmaceutical, or academic field.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### 09/2022 - 08/2024 MSc in Medical Biology - Radboud University, Nijmegen, The Netherlands

- ✓ <u>Specialisation</u>: Science, Management and Innovation
- ✓ GPA result: 7.63/10.00
- ✓ <u>Principal subjects</u>: Future of health, How Health Systems Work, Sustainable Innovation Management, Molecular and Cellular Neurobiology, Molecular Therapy, Trends in Stem Cell Biology
- ✓ <u>Master thesis</u>: «Potential added value of home telemonitoring technology in elderly care», GPA result: **8.00/10.00**

#### 09/2016 - 06/2020 BSc in Biology - Lomonosov Moscow State University (MSU), Moscow, Russia

- ✓ <u>Specialisation</u>: Human and Animal Physiology
- ✓ GPA result: 4.83/5.00
- ✓ <u>Principal subjects</u>: Human and animal physiology, Electrophysiology of excited cells, Physiology of central nervous and visceral systems, Physiology of circulation, Biochemistry, Immunology, Genetics, Microbiology, Embryology
- ✓ <u>Skills</u>: qPCR, RT-PCR, gel electrophoresis, wire myography, western blotting, ELISA,HPLC, microscopy, cell culture, immunohistochemistry, intracellular recording (microelectrodes, patch clamp), behaviour tests (open field test, elevated plus maze, light-dark box test)
- ✓ <u>Bachelor thesis</u>: «Role of TASK-1 channels in arterial tone regulation in different organs in rats», GPA result: 5.00/5.00

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# 10/2024 - current Part-time staff while searching for a life sciences position Renato's Pizzeria - Nijmegen, The Netherlands

- ✓ Providing customer service
- √ Selling the restaurant's menu

#### 02/2024 - 08/2024 Intern at <u>Digital Transformation of Rehabilitation Care</u>

#### HAN University of Applied Sciences - Nijmegen, The Netherlands

- ✓ Added value research of home telemonitoring in elderly care based on the HTA framework presented onto the Quadruple aim
- ✓ Deployment of surveys (22) in Dutch and interviewing (7) medical professionals in English on their home telemonitoring experience/attitude
- ✓ Cost-effectiveness analysis (Markov model cohort simulation) on home telemonitoring in the Netherlands

#### 02/2023 - 08/2023 Intern at Neuronal Networks of Memory

#### **Donders Institute - Nijmegen, The Netherlands**

- ✓ In vivo Ca²+ imaging of the retrosplenial cortex in mice during head-fixed virtual social learning using two-photon microscopy
- ✓ Management of laboratory animals (GCaMP6 transgenic mice, handling & feeding, craniotomy)
- ✓ Computational analysis of the obtained data (Python, DeepLabCut)

#### Assistant at the Science Department of the Contract Research Organization 08/2021 - 08/2022

#### **LABMGMU**, LLC - Moscow, Russia

- ✓ Developing designs, synopses, protocols, investigator's brochures for more than 35 phase I, II, III clinical trials and bioequivalence trials
- ✓ More than 30 user interviews (testing the readability of pharmaceuticals' package leaflets)
- ✓ Advising on the number & design of (pre-)clinical studies for pharma clients
- ✓ Project management (control of the deadlines; compliance with the sponsor's requirements)
- ✓ Computational analysis of the obtained data (STATISTICA, GraphPad Prism)

#### 10/2020 - 10/2021 Junior Research Assistant at Faculty of Biology

### Lomonosov Moscow State University - Moscow, Russia

- ✓ Physiological experiments (wire myography technique, rat coronary and renal arteries)
- ✓ Molecular experiments (RNA extraction, reverse transcription, qPCR, western blotting)
- ✓ Cell and tissue culture experiments (cultivation of arteries in the presence of methoxamine, isoproterenol, and H2O)
- ✓ Management of laboratory animals (Wistar rats: housing, care, breeding)
- ✓ Statistical analysis of the obtained data (STATISTICA, GraphPad Prism)
- ✓ Project management (experiment and research strategy planning)
- ✓ Presentation of the results at the virtual conference ARTERY20, 23-24 October 2020, and at the Conference "Lomonosov-2021", 12-23 April 2021

#### **SCIENTIFIC JOURNAL PUBLICATIONS**

- 1. Shvetsova Anastasia A., Lazarenko Varvara S., Gaynullina Dina K., Tarasova Olga S., Schubert Rudolf (2022). TWIK-Related Acid-Sensitive Potassium Channels (TASK-1) Emerge as Contributors to Tone Regulation in Renal Arteries at Alkaline pH. Frontiers in physiology, 13: 895863. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphys.2022.895863
- 2. Lazarenko Varvara, Shvetsova Anastasia, Gaynullina Dina, Schubert Rudolph (2020). TASK-1 Channels Play an Anticontractile Role in Rat Septal Coronary Artery Under Pharmacological Blockade of Endothelium. Artery Research, 26(S1): S58. https://doi.org/10.2991/artres.k.201209.048
- 3. Borzykh A.A., Kuzmin I.V., Kiryukhina O.O., Selivanova E.K., Shvetsova A.A., Lazarenko V.S., Los-Arkos Uvarova S., Nesterenko A.M., Tarasova O.S. (2020). Voluntary running training of female rats during gestation: characteristics of an experimental model [in Russian]. Aviakosmicheskaya i Ekologicheskaya Meditsina, 54(2): 89-95. https://www.elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=42721639

## **CERTIFICATES**

2023	A FELASA accredited course on Laboratory Animal Science (EU function B) at Radbouldumc
2021	An upgrade training on ICH guidelines on Good Clinical Practice (GCP) at LABMGMU

#### ACADEMIC HONORS AND AWARDS

2022-2024	Awarded Orange Tulip Scholarship for the studies at Radboud University
2020-2021	Awarded MSU Increased State Academic Scholarship for scientific and academic achievements
2021	Second prize-winner in the Lomonosov Universiade on modern problems of biology

#### **DIGITAL SKILLS**

Python (beginner), DeepLabCut, STATISTICA, GraphPad Prism, Rotor-Gene Q Series, and MS Office softwares

#### **LANGUAGES**

Russian (native), English (fluent –  $C_2$ ), German (intermediate –  $B_1$ - $B_2$ ), Dutch (low intermediate –  $A_2$ - $B_1$ ), French (beginner -  $A_1$ )

#### **VOLUNTEERING ACTIVITY**

2024	Mentorship of the international exchange and Master's students at the Radboud Intro
2023	Organization of the BBB Career Event 2023, Nijmegen
2022-2023	Organization of volleyball tournaments in the international volleyball group at Radboud
2018-2021	Mentorship of the first-year students at Faculty of Biology, MSU, Moscow

#### **HOBBIES**

Animals (horses & dogs), volleyball, reading, drawing, guitar playing, traveling